(650) 793-1051 grmsingl

grmsingh@yahoo.com

1055 Manet Dr. #80, Sunnyvale CA 94087

https://swiftgurmeet.github.io/resume/

Summary

I've recently invested significant effort to learn about machine learning and data science. I have worked as a VLSI design engineer for 25 years. My strengths include good communication and analytical skills, quick learning and ingenuity.

Experience

[2015-2018] MACHINE LEARNING PROFESSIONAL

- · Python, R, bit of Scala, Swift
- · Tensorflow, Keras, NumPy
- · CNN, RNN, GBM
- Expert Linux User

Coursera courses:

- · Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- Structuring Machine Learning Projects
- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyper-parameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization
- Convolution Neural Networks
- · Sequence Models
- Machine Learning
- Machine Learning With Big Data
- Practical Machine Learning
- R Programming
- Statistical Inference
- · Reproducible Research
- Regression Models
- Functional Programming Principles in Scala
- · Object Oriented Programming in Java
- · Graph Analytics for Big Data
- Hadoop Platform and Application Framework
- The Data Scientist's Toolbox
- · Getting and Cleaning Data
- · Exploratory Data Analysis
- · Developing Data Products
- · Introduction to Big Data
- Introduction to Big Data Analytics
- HTML, CSS and Javascript for Web Developers



[2016-2017] CONSULTANT, ZGLUE INC. (2 SILICONS SUCCESSES)

• IOT silicon: Physical design, methodology.

[2014-2015] QUALCOMM TECHNOLOGIES, SENIOR STAFF ENGINEER (SILICON SUCCESS)

Audio Codec physical design. Beat the schedule. Received two Qualstars.

[2012-2013] CADENCE DESIGN SYSTEMS, STAFF APPLICATION ENGINEER

Developed rtl2gds flow (14nm/finFET); proven on A9/Neon ARM core.

[2011-2012] SANDFORCE INC., PRINCIPAL ENGINEER (SILICON SUCCESS)

Physical design implementation, methodology and flow development.

[2008-2011] CONTRACTOR/ENGINEER @(MULTIPLE) (3 SILICON SUCCESES)

• Physical design methodology and flow development; WiFi ASIC design.

[2006-2008] TERANETICS, PRINCIPAL ENGINEER (SILICON SUCCESS)

130nm 10GBASE-T PHY ASIC design.

[2004-2006] AIRGO NETWORKS, PHYSICAL DESIGN MANAGER (SILICON SUCCESS)

Multiple WiFi ASIC design, project management.

[2001-2004] TRANSMETA, SENIOR MEMBER OF TECHNICAL STAFF

Efficeon CPU circuit and physical design

[1999-2001] SUN MICROSYSTEMS, MEMBER, TECHNICAL STAFF (SILICON SUCCESS)

UltraSparc III/V CPU circuit design.

[1997-99] INTEL CORPORATION, DESIGN ENGINEER (2 SILICON SUCCESSES)

Pentium III/Xeon CPU circuit design

[1994-97] ST MICROELECTRONICS, DESIGN ENGINEER (2 SILICON SUCCESSES)

SRAMs, Real Time Clock design.

Education

[1989-93] M.ENGG., ELECTRICAL COMM., INDIAN INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE (ALUMNI MEDAL)

[1986-89] B.SC., PHYSICS, DELHI UNIVERSITY (GOLD MEDAL)